(upbeat music)
- Hello, English learners, and welcome back
to another great lesson with English pod.
My name is Marko.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we're bringing
you a great intermediate
lesson with some
really useful vocabulary.
- Some vocabulary you
can use to describe your job.
- Yes, this is a really
common situation when you,
someone asks you what you
do, and you have to tell them.
- Exactly, so today's
lesson is all about facts.
- So before we jump into our dialogue,
let's start with our vocabulary preview.
- Vocabulary preview.
- We have two simple
phrases today that you'll
hear in our dialogue for
our vocabulary preview.
The first one is VP, VP.
So the VP of a company
is the vice president.
- The vice president, exactly.
- Yeah, simple little acronym.
- And the next word is Fortune 500 Company.
- Fortune 500 Company.
- So a Fortune 500
Company is, I'll let you explain.
(laughs)
Well, Fortune Magazine ranks the
500 biggest companies in the US.
- So a Fortune 500 Company basically is
one of the 500 biggest companies in the US.
- Okay, that's simple.
- Yep.
- All right, well with those
words, it sounds like we're
going to be talking to
some important people today.
- Yes, we are gonna be talking
to some important people.
So let's listen to our
dialogue for the first time.
Now it's gonna be a little bit fast,
but you don't have to worry about it.
- 'Cause we'll come back and
explain all of the important vocabulary.
(upbeat music)
- Oh, look, there's
Caroline and a boyfriend.
She's always going on
about him at the office.
Great, they sell us.
I come in this way.
- Oh, man.
- Jessica Arthur, hi.
I'd like you to meet my boyfriend, Greg.
He's the VP of quality and safety
for a top Fortune 500 food company.
Nice to meet you.
This is my husband, Arthur.
- Hey, how's it going?
- Hello.
- Caroline talks about you all the time.
I guess he must be pretty busy at work.
- Well, yeah, VP position
is not easy to know.
(laughs)
High implement policies
and procedures nationwide,
various departments, as well as trained
junior managers in FDA and EPA regulations.
I also have to oversee daily operations
of our quality control
for the entire East Coast.
That alone means I have
1,500 employees under me.
(laughs)
- Yeah, that sounds exciting.
- And what about you, Arthur?
What do you do for a living?
- Oh, I'm on top gun pilot.
(upbeat rock music)
- All right, great music for
our dialogue again, huh?
- Chosen by.
- By more.
- Of course.
- Yeah, top gun is one of
my all time favorite movies.
And top gun pilot, what a cool profession.
- An excellent profession, much
cooler than being like the VP.
- Yeah, boring, yeah.
- Anyway, this guy was a
bit of a jerk, don't you think?
- Yeah, you can tell a little bit of
the sarcastic tone he had in his voice.
- Definitely, but he did
use some interesting
phrases and we can
talk about those now.
- Right, so let's take a
look at language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
Our first word for language
takeaways is implement.
- Implement.
- Let's listen to some examples of this
word to help us understand its meaning.
- Example one.
- Our company has to
implement this cell strategy.
- Example two.
- Several be responsible
for implementing the plan.
- Example three.
- Our implemented several new policies.
- Okay, great examples and just in case
to implement means to put into action.
- Exactly.
- Our second word for
language takeaways, policies.
- Policy is policies.
- Policies.
- So policies are basically
rules and regulations.
- Exactly, formal rules.
- For a company or an organization.
- Exactly, policies, great.
- Third word, oversee.
- Oversea.
- So when you oversee
operations, it means--
- Like you watch it to make sure it's okay.
- You supervise it.
- This is an excellent word to use
when you wanna talk about
your job responsibilities.
- Right.
- Oversea.
- Great.
And our last word for language
takeaway, it's kind of tricky.
So let's listen to how it
was used in our dialogue.
- That alone means I have
1,500 employees under me.
(chuckling)
That alone means I have
1,500 employees under me.
(chuckling)
- So this guy has 1,500 employees under
him, meaning he supervises 1,500 employees.
- Right, he manages 1,500 employees.
- He must be a busy man.
- Yes, for 1,500 employees.
- How many employees do
you have under you, Erica?
- But two, yeah, not
quite as much as 1,500.
- Yeah, guess I'm not a
bp player yet, right, hey?
- Not yet, but you will.
- Okay.
- All right, so with this in mind, we
are ready to listen to our dialogue
for a second time, and this
time, it's gonna be slower.
- Oh, look, there's
Caroline and a boyfriend.
She's always going on
about him at the office.
Oh, great, they saw us.
They're coming this way.
- Oh, man.
- Jessica, Arthur, hi.
I'd like you to meet my boyfriend, Greg.
He's the VP of quality and safety
for a top Fortune 500 food company.
Nice to meet you.
This is my husband, Arthur.
- Hey, how's it going, though?
- Caroline talks about you all the time.
- I guess you must be pretty busy at work.
- Well, yeah, VP position
is not easy, you know.
I implement policies and
procedures nationwide
of various departments as well as trained
junior managers in FDA and EPA regulations.
I also have to oversee daily operations
of our quality control
for the entire East Coast.
That alone means I have
1,500 employees under me.
- Wow, yeah, that sounds exciting.
- And what about you, Arthur?
What do you do for a living?
- Oh, I'm a top gun pilot.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, great stuff.
With this, now we can start
with our fluency builder for today.
- Fluency builder.
We heard some excellent
phrases in this dialogue.
Some phrases that
sound really natural, hey?
- Yes, especially the first
one that we have today
is, whenever someone
talks and talks and talks
and just and continuously talks
without stopping, you would say,
- She's always going on
about him at the office.
- This is a really natural way of
saying, keeps talking about, right?
- Keep talking about him.
- So we have a few examples
of how this phrase works.
Let's listen.
- Example one.
- My boss is always going on
about how we need to save money.
It's all he talks about.
- Example two.
- Gary is always going on about his kids.
He's always talking
about how smart they are.
- Example three.
- My mom is always going on
about how I should get married.
- Okay, excellent, it's clear now.
- Yes.
- Okay, so let's move on to
our second phrase for today.
And this is a great one to use whenever
you meet someone for the first time.
- Or when you start to talk
to someone for the first time.
- Great.
- Hey, how's it going?
- So this is a really relaxed and
natural way of saying, how are you?
- How are you?
- Yeah.
- So yeah, you can just
say, hey, how's it going?
- Yep, great.
- Really natural sounding.
- Now our third phrase is the
most important one of our dialogue.
- Yes.
- And it's a really common situation.
- When someone asks you
about your job, they might say this.
- Who are there?
What do you do for a living?
- So this is a really great way of asking,
what work do you do or what is your job?
- Yes, and now I know a lot of
students sometimes say, what is your job?
- Yeah, and that is, it's kind
of correct, but not really.
- It doesn't sound very natural.
So you want to use what do you
do or what do you do for a living?
- Sounds great.
- That's the way you ask
someone, what is their job?
- And that's how you sound, super natural.
- Okay, so we're ready
now to listen to our dialogue
last time, and now you are
ready to understand everything.
(upbeat music)
- Oh, look, there's
Caroline and a boyfriend.
She's always going on
about him at the office.
- Great, they saw us.
They come in this way.
- Oh man.
- Jessica Arthur, hi.
I'd like you to meet my boyfriend Greg.
He's the VP of quality and safety
for a top Fortune 500 food company.
Nice to meet you.
This is my husband Arthur.
- Hey, how's it going?
- Hello.
- Caroline talks about you all the time.
I guess he must be pretty busy at work.
- Well, yeah, VP position
is not easy to know.
(laughing)
High implement policies
and procedures nationwide.
Various departments, as well as train
junior managers and FDA and EPA regulations.
I also have to oversee daily operations
of our quality control
for the entire East Coast.
That alone means I have
1500 employees under me.
(laughing)
- Yeah, that sounds exciting.
- And what about you Arthur?
What do you do for a living?
- Oh, I'm a top gun pilot.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, so I have a little
challenge for listeners today.
What is it?
Two challenges, okay?
The first one, who performs the song
that you heard and what is the song called?
- Okay, I don't know the answer, so I'm
looking forward to seeing what's users do.
And the second one is, what is the
number one company in the Fortune 500?
- Oh, I also don't know this answer.
Two great questions, so I
expect to see your answers
on the comments page, but also we
want to know about your profession.
- Yes, tell us about your job.
Tell us what you do and
use some of the great
phrases you learned today
to describe your answer.
- Great, so we hope to see you there,
but we're out of time now, so
we'll see everyone at EnglishPod.
com, leave all your questions,
and of course, all the comments.
- And Marco and I are always
around to answer your questions.
- Well, until then, it's goodbye.
(upbeat music)